前哨基地电影集团公司
鲍勃前哨基地电影公司
内尔・博格尔 电影
主演：爱德华・诺顿
主演：保罗・吉亚玛提
主演：杰西卡・贝尔
魔 术 师
卢夫斯・塞维尔
导演：内尔・博格尔
是她！我知道是她！
It's her! I know it's her!
她有话要对我们说
She wants to tell us something!
我们得有所行动
We must do something! Please.
我代表国王陛下与维也纳市…
In the name of his Imperial Majesty and the city of Vienna,
在此逮捕爱德华艾维兹
I hereby arrest Edward Abramowitz.
也就是魔术师艾森瀚
Also known as Eisenheim the Illusionist.
罪名是违反秩序
On charges of disturbing public order, charlatanism,
诈欺与危害安全
and threats against the Empire.
放开他
Leave him alone!
他们抓了他
They're arresting him!
他们逮捕艾森瀚
They're arresting Eisenheim!
乌尔探长求见
Chief Inspector Uhl.
你迟到了
You're late.
我很抱歉，王子殿下
My apologies, your Highness.
我还在努力解决一些问题
I was attending to the loose ends of the case.
还有要解决的问题？
Are there still loose ends?
不多了
Very few.
他又表演了吗？
Did he do it again?
怎么办到的？
How does he do it?
恐怕我还是不清楚
I'm afraid I still don't know.
你没问他？
Did you ask him?
他此时什么都不肯说
He's not talking at this point.
是吗？我相信你自有办法
Well, I'm sure you have methods for that kind of thing.
我要你尽速结案
I want you to put an end to it.
你怎么样都该有些线索
Surely you have something on him.
有他的来历吗
Something from his past?
是的，我查到了
Yes. Yes, I think I do.
我们对他的一生了若指掌
In fact we know all about his life.
遍访每位认识他的人
We've spoken to almost everyone who ever knew him.
他小时候曾遇见一位魔术师旅人
As a boy, I'm told he had a chance encounter with a traveling magician.
孩子
Boy.
其中一个版本是那人
One version of the story was that the man
后来与树…一同消失了
himself then vanished along with the tree.
没人知道实际发生什么事
Who knows what actually happened?
旁人开始相信他真拥有特殊能力
People began to think he had some kind of special power,
或是他的确与众不同
or at least that he was a bit different.
接着，他遇见了她
And then he met her.
别弄掉了
Don't drop it.
小心，你要摔倒啦
Careful, you're going to trip.
掉吧，你这穷酸鬼
Drop it, you muck-snipe.
注意那个洞，臭小子
Oh! Watch out for that hole, alley rat!
掉下来！
Drop it!
挑一张牌，把牌放回去
Pick a card. Put it back in the deck.
现在你看
Now, watch.
特森女爵？你不能来这种地方
Duchess Von Teschen, you can't be in a place like this.
他们是粗人，记得你的身份
They're peasants. Remember who you are.
她被带回了城堡，两人还被禁止相见
She was brought back to the castle and they were forbidden to see each other.
不久后，他们还是偷偷往来
But soon they were doing just that.
接下来几年，两人总有方法私会
Over the next few years they could always find a way to be together.
快，快来
Quick, come on.
中国的魔术师能把东西变不见了
In China there's a magician that could make anything disappear.
无论是房子、马车，什么都可以
A house, a wagon, anything.
我们要去见他
We'll go visit him.
他们不能阻止我们在一起
They can't stop us if we want to be together.
他们永远都找不到我们
They'll never find us.
你保证会带我一起走吗
Do you promise you'll take me with you?
总有一天，我会的
One day I will.
有一天我们要一起逃离
One day we'll run away together.
我们会一起消失不见
We'll disappear.
打开它是有秘诀的
There's a secret way to open it.
我想要这张照片
I wanted a picture.
苏菲，你在那吗？
Sophie, are you there?
我们得快点！他们追来了！
We must hurry! They're coming!
特森女爵！
Duchess von Teschen!
让我们消失，让我们消失
Make us disappear. Make us disappear.
特森女爵！
Duchess von Teschen!
停下来
Stop. Stop.
别这么做，让我走
Don't do this. Let me go. Let go.
不！求求你，放手！
No! Please, let go!
不！放她走，求求你！
No! Let her go, please!
放手！停下来！
Let go! Stop it!
苏菲！
Sophie!
爱德华！
Eduard!
苏菲！    -爱德华！
-Sophie!    -Eduard!
苏菲
Sophie.
远离她，否则就抓你和你的家人
Stay away from her or next time we'll arrest you and your family.
后来发生的事仍是难解的谜
What happened next remains a mystery.
可确定的是…他走遍世界
We do know that he traveled the world.
当他开始公开表演魔术时
That he began to perform his magic in public.
改名为艾森瀚
That he changed his name to Eisenheim.
近十五年后，他在维也纳现身
And then almost fifteen years later he appeared in Vienna.
生与死，空间与时间，命运与机遇
Life and death, space and time, fate and chance.
以上都是宇宙的力量
These are the forces of the universe.
今晚，各位女士、先生
Tonight, ladies and gentleman,
容我介绍一位能解开宇宙奥秘
I present to you a man who has unlocked these mysteries.
远从世界尽头…
From the furthest corners of the world
来自…黑魔法仍主宰之处
where the dark arts still hold sway,
能扭转自然法则之人
he returns to us to demonstrate how nature's laws may be bent.
请艾森瀚出场
I give you... Eisenheim.
谁能借我一条手帕
Might I borrow a handkerchief from someone?
女士，就是你
You, Madam.
谢谢你，请稍安勿躁
Thank you. Ah, be patient.
现在，请容我来验证时间
Now, if you please, I would like to continue with an examination of time.
生命被注入的那刻起，只能任其发展
From the moment we enter this life we are in the flow of it.
我们能测量、标记，却无法违抗
We measure it and we mark it but we cannot defy it.
无法加速或放慢
We cannot even speed it up or slow it down.
还是我们可以…？
Or can we?
我们都曾有过一种感受
Have we not each experienced a sensation
美好时光过得特别快
that a beautiful moment seemed to pass too quickly?
总希望它能持续
And wished that we could make it linger?
时间在无聊日子里过得特别慢
Or felt time slow on a dull day
希望可以加快
and wished that we could speed things up a bit?
我保证它们是真的
I assure you, they're quite real.
这位女士，你的手帕呢？
And you, Madam, where is your handkerchief?
好极了！真精彩
Bravo! Very good.
施舍我们，求求你，施舍我们东西
Give us something. Please, please, give us something.
求求你    -怎么回事？
-Please.    -What's all this?
我们很穷
We're poor.
你们认为自己很穷？
Do you think you're poor?
是的
Yes.
我让你们看样东西，你们不贫穷
I want to show you something. You're not poor.
这里有你们所需的一切
You have everything that you need right here.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是你的，这也是
And that's yours. And this too.
早啊    -早安
-Good morning.    -Good morning.
要咖啡吗？    -不用
-Coffee?    -No.
酥卷呢？我有两块
Strudel? I have two.
都不用，谢谢
Nothing, thank you.
你看来很怡然自得
You look very pleased with yourself.
票房如何
How are the receipts?
还不错，卖了四分之三
Not bad. A three-quarter house.
做得好
Well done.
我们还会更好
But we're going to do better than that.
听听这个，听好了
Listen to this. Listen.
无疑地，他神奇的演出…
"There is no argument that his uncanny displays separate
使他有别于随处可见的术士
him from the ranks of garden variety stage wizards.
他的部分演出…甚至超越了幻象
Some of his effects transcend mere illusion
已臻艺术之境
and approach the realm of art.
他年纪轻轻，却已是大师
He is very young to be so masterful.
懂了吗？这评论包准让剧院满座
You see? We'll pack the house with this review.
我们就要赚到超乎你想像的钱了
We are going to make more money than you ever dreamed of.
那是人造的，再用树皮包起来？
But if it was mechanical, maybe he had it wrapped in some kind of bark?
我当然也想到了
Oh, yeah, of course I thought of that.
我只是想不透蝴蝶到底怎么变的
It's the butterflies I'm trying to work out.
还用说吗，钢丝呀
Oh, for Pete's sake, invisible wire.
那太明显了
Too obvious.
你今晚派了多少人
How many men have you detailed for tonight?
里面八人，外面八人
We have eight men inside, another eight out front.
也许你下回再研究蝴蝶吧
Perhaps you'll get another look at your butterflies.
检查后面十排
Check the last ten rows there.
你！别碰那东西！把它放下
You! Don't touch that! Put that down!
艾森瀚先生
Ah, Herr Eisenheim.
你是谁，以为自己在做什么？
Who are you and what do you think you're doing?
我是华特乌尔探长
I'm Chief Inspector Walter Uhl .
我正在检查你的剧院
and I'm inspecting your theatre
我看过你的表演
I've seen you perform.
很让人难忘，让人印象非常深刻
Very impressive. Very impressive.
有什么指教吗？探长先生
How can we help you, Inspector?
你将很荣幸得知…
You will be honored to know that the Crown Prince plans
王子殿下今晚将莅临你的演出
to attend your performance tonight.
王子殿下？
The Crown Prince?
是的，所以我们得做安检
Yes! So, obviously we have to inspect the theatre.
刺客可能会嫌那太小，不是吗？
I think that one's a bit small for an assassin, don't you?
是的，关于柳橙树…
Yes, the orange tree.
我曾看过类似的演出
You know, I have seen things like this before
但和你的完全不同，无人能及
but never one like that. Extraordinary.
谢谢
Thank you.
我一直想不通是怎么回事
I have been puzzling over how it works,
尤其是蝴蝶飞起来
especially how the butterflies fly.
我保证会守密
I assure you your secret is safe with me.
毕竟我是执法人员
I'm an officer of the law after all,
私底下也是业余魔术师
and a bit of an amateur conjourer.
你说真的？
Are you really?
是的，牌戏、钱币，还懂一点手技
Yes. Well, card tricks, coins, uh, slight of hand, yes?
没啥了不起，也许你能给点提示
But nothing fancy. Perhaps you'll give me a tip?
好啊，教你我很喜欢的一招
Yes, all right. I'll show you one I'm very fond of.
你会赌博吗？
Are you a gambling man?
偶尔会
On occasion, yes.
我以柳橙树的秘诀与你打赌
I will bet you the secret of the orange tree
我能猜到你放在哪只手
that I can guess which hand you place this in every time.
好极了
Excellent.
放掌心，手抬起碰一下额头
Put it in your fist, raise your hand against your forehead,
全神贯注想像一下画面
concentrate on it, form a mental picture.
好的    -想好了吗？
-Yes.    -Have you got it?
是…
Yes.
手伸到前方
Put your hands in front of you.
在左手
It's in your left.
这！    -只是好运猜到？也许是
-Well !    -A lucky guess, perhaps.
有人在旁提示你吧？
You have a confederate who signals you.
不，比这简单多了
No. It's more primitive than that.
是吗？
Uh-huh.
当你抬起手时，血液会往下流
When you raise your hand to your head, the blood drains from it.
每次都会变白
It will be paler every time.
喔，我喜欢这招
Oh, oh, I like that very much.
请你笑纳
Please take it with my compliments.
当然，谢了，嗯，血往下流
Why, thank you. Eh, the blood drains.
探长，如果你不介意…
Now, Inspector, if you don't mind,
我得准备今晚的演出了
I've got to prepare for tonight's performance.
哈
Ah.
起立恭迎利奥波德王子殿下
Please stand for his Imperial Highness, Crown Prince Leopold.
今晚的压轴就让我们探讨灵魂
I thought we might end this evening with a discussion of the soul.
伟大的宗教都曾谈到灵魂的存在
All of the greatest religions speak
超越了生死
of the soul's endurance beyond the end of life.
死亡的意义到底为何？
So, what then does it mean to die?
我需要一位自愿者上台
I need a volunteer from the audience.
一位不畏死亡之人，有人吗？请
Someone not afraid of death. Please, someone?
我保证不会有悲剧上身
I assure you no tragedy will befall you.
真是荣幸，特森女爵
It's an honor, Duchess Von Teschen.
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know me?
不
No.
你确定我们没见过？
You're quite certain that we've never met before?
是的，当然
Yes, of course.
请凝视我的双眼，不要瞄别处
Now please gaze directly into my eyes. Look nowhere else.
朝自己挥手，转个圈
Wave to yourself. Turn in a circle.
现在，向自己鞠躬
Now, bow to yourself.
远离
Away.
他们一定很欣赏你
They must have liked you.
等了你快五分钟
They've waited for you nearly five minutes.
殿下，容我为你介绍魔术师艾森瀚
Your Highness, may I introduce Eisenheim the Illusionist?
表演得好
Well done.
感谢你的莅临，希望你喜欢
Thank you for coming. I hope you enjoyed it.
我们不只是喜欢而已
Oh, we more than enjoyed it.
还引发一阵辩论，不是吗？
Stimulated great debate amongst us, hasn't it?
除了你的助手特森女爵
Except of course for your assistant, Duchess Von Teschen.
你似乎把她吓呆了
You seemed to have struck her quite speechless.
了不起的技艺，你催眠了她吗？
A feat in itself. Did you hypnotize her?
一点点
In a fashion.
我倒想学这个戏法
I'd like to learn that trick.
瑞纳觉得你有超能力
Rainier here thinks you have supernatural powers.
你声称你有超能力吗
Do you claim supernatural powers?
我从没这么说
I've never said anything of that kind.
你不介意我问一两个问题吧
Then you won't mind a question or two.
我们别再煞风景了
Now let's not ruin it.
你毋须泄露我猜不到的事情
You needn't divulge anything I can't guess.
悉听尊便
As you wish.
你的助手穿上袍子…躲在镜子后方
Your assistants are behind a mirror somewhere in robes obviously.
镜框里的光线能照出他，还是角镜？
Lights in the frame perhaps to illuminate them, or angled mirrors?
这是可行方法之一
That would be one way to do it.
除了幽灵部分，我都懂
I think I understand it all except the ghost.
那真的非常非常精彩
That was very, very good.
还会再大驾光临吗？
Another viewing perhaps?
你下次得来霍夫堡皇宫
You must come to the Hofburg next time.
我们会有个美好的夜晚
We'll make an evening of it.
我的荣幸
That will be my pleasure.
那就来吧，是吧，苏菲？
So be it. Sophie?
我下次会召集智囊团
And we'll gather our best minds next time.
届时你的挑战可大了
You'll really have a challenge then.
我会准备特别的演出
Then I'll prepare something special.
也许我会把你变不见了
Perhaps I'll make you disappear.
我的老天，他拱她上台时…
Oh, my God, when he volunteered her I heard the crashing sound
我听到成堆钱币撒在身上的声音
of money falling on me in piles.
每位维也纳女人会巴不得与你同台
Every lady of means in Vienna will want to get up there with you now.
他真是爱现
What a showoff.
他的父王看到后，搞不好会气死
His father would have died if he had seen such a display.
她看来似乎也不太高兴
She didn't seem too happy about it either.
她最好快习惯
Well, she'd better get used to it.
怎么回事？    -据说她快嫁给他了
-How's that?    -Word is she'll marry him soon.
真的吗？    -我会说她得自求多福
-Really?    -Taking her chances if you ask me.
怎么说？
Why?
他喜欢对女人拳打脚踢
He likes to give his lady friends a good thrashing now and again.
听说他曾把一人推下阳台
People say he pushed one of them off a balcony
只为了掩饰他曾痛揍过她
just to cover the beating he had given her.
艾森瀚先生的信
For Herr Eisenheim.
你好，苏菲
Hello, Sophie.
我上台时，你马上就认出我了
When I was on the stage, you knew me right away.
想了一下，是的，我的确认出你
It took me a moment but, yes, I knew.
你大可说些话
You could have said something.
我认为你总会想到的
I thought you'd figure it out eventually.
是，我该如此
Yes, I would have.
我该在某夜自愿…
I would have come another night, volunteered,
上台打招呼
walked right on stage and said hello.
那你很快就得打包走人了
And then you'd really have had to move quickly.
我以为你会这么做
I suspect you would have.
我不懂
I don't understand why.
就如同…你约在马车碰面的理由
Perhaps for the same reasons you find it prudent to meet in a carriage.
这是我和他们玩的游戏
It's just a game I have to play with them.
我走到哪都被跟踪
I'm followed everywhere.
美其名曰是为了保护我
It's-it's supposed to be for my protection.
是的，我听说你有喜讯了？
Yes. So, I hear congratulations are in order.
为什么？
What for?
大家都说你会当上王妃
They say you'll be the princess.
根本没这回事
It's not decided at all.
是吗？
Ah.
我想也并非不无道理
It makes a certain sense, I suppose.
我们已相识许久，彼此家人也是
We've known each other for years and of course our families.
他非常聪明，太聪明也不是什么好事
He's very intelligent. A little too intelligent for his own good.
你很幸运，知道吗？你是自由的
You're lucky, you know. To have broken free as you did.
我常希望自己
I often wish that I had...
希望什么？
Wished what?
我常希望能再见你一面
I wished that I would see you again.
现在你见到了
And now you have.
是的，我见到了
Yes, now I have.
我期待在霍夫堡再见到你
I look forward to seeing you again at the Hofburg.
到时见了
Until then.
这是特森女爵的报告
Here's the report on Duchess Von Teschen.
嗯，有啥有趣的？
Mmm. Anything interesting?
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
那个魔术师？
The magician?
他们绕了半小时，他先在戏院下车
They drove around for half an hour, then he got out near the theatre.
接下来怎么做？
What do you want us to do?
一起喝一杯？
Join us for a drink?
请坐
Please.
想不想吃些什么、喝些什么？
You like something to eat, something to drink, mmm?
不了，谢谢
No, thank you.
艾森瀚先生…我要问你一件事
Herr Eisenheim, I'm going to ask you a question
听起来也许不友善
that may not seem friendly.
但你放心，我其实出于好意
But I assure you, in fact, is.
你和特森女爵是什么关系？
What is your relationship with the Duchess Von Teschen?
你没说错，这问题很不友善
You're right, that doesn't seem friendly.
这正是我的重点
Oh, but that is precisely my point.
你想别人会怎么看马车里的幽会？
For, you see, where others might judge a discreet carriage ride
既然表面看来很可疑
for what it seemed to be,
我很乐意调查真相
I am willing to find out what it actually was.
好吧，我们是小时的玩伴
All right. We were childhood acquaintances.
玩伴？
Acquaintances?
童年时的朋友，我的父亲是家具工
Childhood friends. My father was a cabinetmaker.
他曾为她的家族制作家具
He made the furniture for her family's house.
我懂了，家具工之子结交了一位…
I see, the cabinet maker's son friends with a--
有什么人不满吗？
Has there been a complaint?
喔，不，不…
Oh, no, no.
如果真有什么不满…
If there'd been a complaint...
我们就不会这样对话了
Well, we'd be having a very, uh, different sort of conversation.
他都靠你处理这类事，不是吗？
Yes. He relies on you for that sort of thing, does he?
我只是单纯的公仆，艾森瀚
I'm a simple public servant, Herr Eisenheim.
我听到的不是如此
That's not what I hear.
我听说你快当上警察总长
I hear you'll be the Chief of Police very soon.
还是维也纳市长？议事大臣？
Maybe Mayor of Vienna? Party Secretary?
他说了才算
All subject to his whim.
你最好希望他不会解散国会…
You better hope he doesn't dissolve the Parliament
在你升官之前
before you get there.
王子殿下有些想法很先进
Now, the Prince has some progressive ideas,
但他会是一位好君主
but he will make a fine Emperor.
听说你们关系良好，我确信你会很好
Well, they say you're very close to him, so I'm sure you'll be fine.
是的，大家都说我与王子关系好
Look-- Yes, indeed, they say that I'm very close to the Prince.
事实摆在眼前，艾森瀚
But the simple truth of the matter is, Herr Eisenheim,
我是肉贩之子
I'm the son of a butcher.
他是王位继承人
He's the heir to the Empire.
我和他能好到哪去？
How close could we be to such as him, Hmm?
你清楚我的重点吗？
Do you see my point?
别傻到以为你可和他们打交道
Don't fool yourself that you can play in their game.
我在底下服务，做了很多很多年
I've served on the edge of it for many, many years
我很确定他们看遍各种手法
and I can tell you with certainty there's no trick they haven't seen.
这样做不值得
It's not worth it.
今晚的贵客不是表演家，而是巫师
My guest tonight is not a showman at all, but rather a wizard
他用灵魂与恶魔交换邪恶力量
who has sold his soul to the devil in return for unholy powers.
或者有人要让我们如此相信
Or so at least some of our friends here would have us believe.
别害怕，所有事情都有解释
But fear not, everything can and will be explained.
所有的谜团都能破解
All mysteries penetrated.
嘿！说得好，说得好
Here, Here. Well said. Well said.
那是国王吗？
Is that the emperor?
是的，你的父亲
Ah, yes, your father.
我不知道他也受邀了
I didn't think he was invited .
很像那位老头
A fair likeness of the old man.
但没那么时髦
Too modern a style for him, of course.
恐怕我不是一位好画家
I'm afraid I'm not much of a painter.
没错，画上没有笔触痕迹
It's true, there are no brush strokes in this painting,
我看得出来
I can see that clearly.
上色效果应是某种化学物质的作用
So to achieve the color some sort of chemical must be interacting, presumably.
袖子里有喷雾器吗？可以看看吗？
Some sort of sprayer up your sleeve? May I?
如果你觉得有必要
If you feel you must.
的确有必要
I do.
就让他好好表演吧
Oh, let the man do his show.
事实摆在眼前，你竟要我呆坐着？
You want me to just sit there when it's so obvious?
我是这么希望
I do.
他试着要愚弄你，而我要启迪你
He tries to trick you. I try to enlighten you.
谁的目的比较高尚？
Which is the more noble pursuit?
可以打光…让王子看得更清楚吗？
May we have the lights please, so his Highness can better see?
利奥波德，让我们看表演
See here, Leopold, let's have a show.
嘿！嘿！
Here, here.
得了，利奥波德，继续吧
Come on, Leopold, get on with it.
好，我要下挑战
Very well, I propose a challenge.
你能不靠这些机关使我们吃惊吗？
Why don't you astonish us, if you can, without all the gadgetry?
如你所愿
As you wish.
你的剑很漂亮，能让我看看吗？
Your sword is very beautiful. Might I see it?
当然
Certainly.
不介意吧？
May I?
力量源自何处？
Where does power flow from?
技巧？命运还是天意？
Skill or destiny, or divine right?
我们都听过石中剑的故事
We all know the story of a sword called Excalibur.
它插在石缝中静止不动
Excalibur's blade was fixed in stone, and there it stayed.
许多伟大的武士都尝试拔剑
Many worthy knights tried to pull the sword from the stone.
亚瑟证明了他的正当性
Only Arthur succeeded proving his right to rule.
谁拔得起剑？
Who can take this sword?
这位先生，你能否拔起这把剑？
You sir, can you take the sword?
一点都不让人意外
No surprise there.
也许你可以，先生
Perhaps you, sir.
不用这么急切，表弟
Not so eager, cousin.
你会很长寿
You shall live a long life.
谢谢你的投入
Thank you for your indulgence.
如果你拔不出，永远别想当上国王
Come now, if you can't pull it out you'll never be Emperor.
你的父亲会活到一百岁
Your father will live to be a hundred.
这把剑的真正主人出现了
The sword to its rightful owner!
今晚的余兴节目到此为止
That's enough light entertainment for this evening.
还有更严肃的话题，请与我共饮
For more serious discussion, please join me for a drink.
把他的表演停掉
Shut him down.
他很受欢迎，王子殿下
Well, he's very popular, your Highness.
我确定你会有办法
I'm sure you'll find a way.
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
我给他想要的
I gave him what he asked for.
你为何鬼迷心窍做这种蠢事？
What would possess you to do something so foolish?
亲爱的特森女爵，你得过来
Duchess Von Teschen, you must come along, my dear.
我们不能让王子久候，喜欢表演吗？
We don't want to keep the Prince waiting. Did you enjoy the show?
棒极了，不是吗？
It was wonderful, wasn't it?
很有娱乐性
It was amusing.
谁告诉你到哪找我
Who told you where to find me?
你的经理
Your manager.
他如果想留在维也纳，就要我帮忙
I told him if he wants to stay in Vienna, you need my help.
所以我要被赶出这城市吗？
Ah, so I'm to be driven from the city, is that it?
很好，再好不过
Good, I shall relish it.
别说了！我是来这里帮你的
Stop it! I came here to try to help you.
为什么？你何必在乎我的事？
Why! Why should you possibly care what happens to me now?
你是我的朋友，我也是你的朋友
You were my friend. I am your friend.
我们只是在很久以前短暂相识
We knew each other very briefly a long time ago.
你根本就不了解我
You don't know me at all.
你何必与我说话？何必自找麻烦？
Then why did you speak to me? Why did you even bother talking-
你一直都戴在身上？
And you kept it all this time.
我常望着你的照片，想像你的去处
I used to sit and stare at your picture trying to imagine where you were.
我梦见我和你离开，直到醒来
At night I'd have dreams I had gone with you,
才意识到自己身在何方
and then I'd wake up and realize where I was.
我梦中的你头发短了点，也没胡须
But in my dreams you had shorter hair and no beard.
你当时离开后去了哪？
Where did you go when you left?
我叔叔在布拉格附近的农场
To my uncle's farm near Prague.
多有异国情调啊！
How exotic.
在俄国、小亚细亚与东方待了多年
I went to Russia, then Asia Minor, and then the Orient for many years.
去了真久
So long.
我一直想回来，只是…
I always meant to return.
我不断想着，也许能在下一处发现
I just- I kept thinking I'd find it around the next corner.
发现什么？
What?
真正的奥秘
A real mystery.
我能看到超凡的事物
I saw remarkable things, but the only mystery
但唯一解不开的奥秘…就是我的心
为何忘不了你
I never solved was why my heart couldn't let go of you.
他希望我同去布达佩斯
He wants me to go to Budapest with him
下周与他宣布订婚
next week to announce our engagement.
他要匈牙利人做后盾
He wants the Hungarians behind him.
他们要拥他为王
They're going to crown him King.
他的父亲想必会很有意见
I'm sure his father will have something to say about that.
他计划推翻自己的父王
He plans to overthrow his father.
这对他很不利，对你也是
That could go very badly for him... and for you.
你不该涉入其中
You shouldn't be involved.
我是他计划中的一部份
I am part of his plan.
要匈牙利人支持，得靠我们两家结盟
He only gets Hungary by aligning himself with my family.
离开他
Leave him.
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
取消婚事和我走
Call it off and come away with me.
或者现在一走了之
Or don't say anything and we'll just go.
只要我们活着，他会追捕我们
As long as we are alive he'll hunt us.
若被他找到会杀死我们的
And when he finds us he'll kill us.
看着我，你真的想与我离开？
Look at me. Do you truly want to leave with me?
是的，我愿意
Yes, I do.
你在这，我早料到我们要关门大吉了
There you are. As I predicted they shut us down.
你满意了吧？你表达立场了
Are you happy now, hmm? You made your point.
票房满不满座，对你根本不重要
It doesn't matter that we were sold out for the whole run.
你终于一吐为快了
No, look. You got it off your chest.
我们有钱吗？
Do we have money?
什么？
What?
我们还有存款吗？
Do we have any money saved?
是，还有一些，本来还能有更多的
Yes, we have some. But we could have had much, much more.
嗯，应该能派上用场
Mmm, it will have to do.
还有第二个户头里的，全部都要
And the second account, all of it.
是的，艾森瀚先生
Of course, Herr Eisenheim.
谢谢！
Thank you.
你确定那是特森女爵吗？
And you have no doubt it was Duchess Von Teschen?
可以拿我的生命担保
I'd stake my life on it.
箱子里有什么？
What was in the suitcase?
我不知道
I don't know.
他在第一台车厢
He's by the first car.
地图会告诉你到哪碰面
The map will show you where to meet.
完事后，你和她先走，我会跟上
When it's done, you'll travel ahead with her and I shall follow.
她清楚这件事的后果吗？
And she understands everything this entails?
完全清楚，时间不多了
Completely. There's not a lot of time.
你知道，我们会跟踪并保护女爵
As you know, we sometimes follow Duchess Von Teschen for her protection.
昨天她与另一男人碰面
Yesterday she was seen in the company of another man.
什么人？
What man?
艾森瀚那位魔术师
Eisenheim, the Illusionist.
他们当时在做什么？
What were they doing?
他们见了面，然后…
Well, they were meeting and, uh--
抚摸？亲吻？还是搞在一起？
Touching? Kissing? Were they fucking?
就我们观察没有，然而我相信…
Not that we observed, no.
他们可能一同计划某些事
However, I have reason to believe that they may be planning something together.
可能是两人要离开
It's possible they may be leaving.
什么都还不明确，殿下
I'm not certain of anything yet, your Highness.
谢谢你，探长
Thank you, Inspector.
我们会再L集更多情报
We can of course acquire more information-
他下午在维也纳陪父亲
He spent the afternoon in Vienna with his father.
他等会才到
He's expected shortly.
真让人意外，我以为你讨厌这里
What a surprise. I thought you didn't like it here.
你大概自以为很聪明、又自主
I suppose you think you're very clever
尤其在交友方面，不是吗？
and very democratic in your friendships, aren't you?
你到底在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你的魔术师朋友，你和他有往来
Your magician friend. I know you've been with him.
没错，我们从小就是朋友
It's true. We've been friends since childhood.
你和所有童年玩伴都上床吗？
You sleep with all your childhood friends?
你这种态度我不回答！
I will not be spoken to this way.
只要我想问，你就得回答
You'll be spoken to as I wish to speak to you.
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
你老大不小了，不是吗？
You're getting quite old, aren't you?
我的母亲十六岁时嫁给我的父亲
You know, my mother was sixteen years old when she married my father.
你还生得出孩子吗？你有什么用处
And you? Can you even bear children?
你想让我难堪吗？
Are you any use at all? Are you trying to embarrass me?
与你无关
It has nothing to do with you.
与我关系可大了！
It has everything to do with me!
如果你和他睡过，就别想上我的床
You will not share my bed if you've slept with him!!
你不懂，我根本不想与你同床
You don't understand. I'm not going to share your bed at all.
我不会和你去布达佩斯
I'm not going to Budapest with you.
我不要被你利用
I don't want to be part of what you're planning.
也不会嫁给你
And I will not marry you.
我假设你没蠢到告诉他任何事
I assume you haven't been so stupid as to tell him anything.
要是你坏了我的好事
'Cause if you disrupt my plans
你也没好处，明白吗？
I will have no further use for you, do you understand?
准备明天去布达佩斯
Now, you will travel to Budapest tomorrow.
我建议你赶快打包，准备上路
I recommend that you are here early packed and ready to go.
别再丢我的脸
Do nothing more to embarrass me.
再见！
Goodbye.
“再见”是什么意思？
What do you mean "goodbye"?
给我回来！
Come back here.
Come back here!
别再忤逆我，婊子！
Don't disobey me again. Whore!
让开，求求你，不要！
Out of my way. Please, don't-- Uugh.
不用了，放着吧，提灯都留下
No, leave that. Leave all the lanterns.
特森女爵！
Duchess Von Tuschen!
在这里！
Over here!
我以为你看到她和他上了火车
I thought you saw her get on the train with him!
不，我们在维也纳
No, sir, we were waiting in Vienna for them.
他们从巴登上车，我们把她认成他
But they left from Barden?. We assumed she was him.
该发电报给王子吗？
Should I wire the Crown Prince in Budapest?
发了！  你是谁？
It's been done! Who are you?
我是她的家庭医师，你是探长吗？
I'm the family's doctor. Are you the Chief Inspector?
我是，你知道这是警方的事吗？
Yes, I am. You understand this is a police matter now?
我当然了解
Of course I understand.
好，好
Good, good.
你判定死因了吗？
You have determined the cause of death?
失血过多
She bled to death.
伤口在左锁骨上方咽喉部位
There's a wound on her throat just above the left collarbone-
可能是匕首或剑
Uh, some knife or sword.
我能看一眼吗？
May I take a look?
探长，这我不能认同
Inspector, l-I will not stand for it.
王子也不会认可的，这不是马戏表演
The Crown Prince will not stand for it. This is not some circus sideshow.
抱歉，你没错
My apologies, of course.
谢谢你，医生
Thank you, doctor.
可能是被抢了，也许是吉普赛人？
Probably robbed. Gypsies maybe?
看看这些钻石，不是不可能
Saw all those diamonds, couldn't say no.
探长，有件事该让你知道
Chief Inspector, there's one thing you should know.
是的，什么事？
Yes, what is that?
我在她衣内发现这颗小宝石
In the folds of her dress I found this small gemstone.
她上周四七点半独自骑着马…
Seen last Thursday at 7:30 p.m. riding without
到皇家狩猎小屋
an escort toward the Imperial Hunting Lodge.
古仕曼说，她抵达时间约八点半
Groomsman said she arrived about 8:30.
她独自一人要做什么？
What was she doing riding alone?
他干的，你知道是他干的
He did this. You know he did.
我知道谁做了什么？
I know who did what?
王子！他杀了她！
The Crown Prince! He killed her.
他有前科，你清楚得很
He's done it before and you know it!
不，我不知道
No, I don't know that. In fact,
我确定不是，他人在布达佩斯
I'm sure he didn't. He's in Budapest.
他在动身前杀了她
He killed her before he left.
恐怕事实无法支持你的假设
I'm afraid the facts don't support your theory.
她本来要离开他
She was leaving him.
为了谁？你吗？    -是的
For who? You? Yes.
别荒谬了，艾森瀚
Don't be absurd, Herr Eisenheim.
他杀她是因为不让她走
He killed her because he couldn't let her go.
她知道他的秘密
She knew his secret.
什么秘密？
What secret?
问你的探长，他知道
Ask your Inspector. He knows.
别再说了
Stop this right now!
你完全堕落了吗？
Are you completely corrupt?
不，就是因为不完全，我建议你…
No, not completely, no, which is
不要指控任何人，尤其是王子
why I'll advise you not to accuse anyone especially his Imperial Highness,
否则，你就等着老死狱中吧
or you'll end up in jail yourself.
让她离开城门的守卫在哪？
Where's the guard who let her out of the gate?
王子殿下带走了
Gone with the Crown Prince.
任何仆人看到她离开吗？
Did any of the servants see her leave?
当时都睡了
All asleep.
那他呢？
What about him?
他替她把马牵到第一个马厩
He uh, he put her horse in the first stall when she arrived.
这一个？
This one?
我们无权过问皇家所有物
We don't have jurisdiction on imperial property.
谢谢，我知道
Thank you. I know.
你在做什么？
So, what are you doing?
查案
Investigating.
你也听到魔术师说的
Listening to that magician, are you?
就我们所知，是他干的
For all we know, he did it.
不，我不这么认为
No, I think not.
王子殿下回来了
The Crown Prince-- He's back.
探长，我们该走了，就是现在
Chief Inspector, we should go. Now.
你查到什么？
And what have you found out?
有人目击她曾独自骑马
She was last seen riding here alone.
根据你的资料，是我赶她出去的
Yes, and based on your information I then threw her out, Chief?.
她是自杀吗？
Did she commit suicide?
不，这是一宗谋杀案
No, it was surely murder.
有任何嫌疑犯吗？
Do you have a suspect?
很快会有的，王子殿下
We will soon, your Highness.
接下来，我们逮捕一人并控告谋杀
Later that week, we arrested a man and charged him with murder.
我知道艾森瀚不会就此服气
But I knew that that wouldn't satisfy Eisenheim.
我让手下继续监视他
I had my men continue to watch him.
他终于走出伤痛，买下一间老戏院
He finally emerged from his grief and bought a rundown theatre.
太完美了
It's perfect.
他开除经理人，并准备新表演
He fired his manager and began preparing for a new kind of show.
他是谁？
Who is he?
我的名字是法兰柯
My name is Frankel.
你从哪来的
Where did you come from?
我来自布隆，父亲是一位镜片磨工
I come from Brunn. My father is a lens grinder there.
你今晚如何来此？
How did you come to be here tonight?
我不知道
I don't know.
你还活着吗？
Are you alive?
能否说说另一个世界？
What can you tell us about the other side?
什么样子？
What's it like?
是呀，跟我们说说
Yes, tell us.
你一定知道什么秘密
You must know things, secret things.
他们似乎不认为这是唬人的
They don't seem to think it's a trick.
艾森瀚的观众向来很热烈
Eisenheim's audience had always been enthusiastic.
他又吸引一批更激情的拥护者
But now he was attracting a more impassioned following.
女士，麻烦你了
Madame, please.
借这些灵魂与表演，艾森瀚证明了…
With these spirts, these manifestations,
灵魂的不朽与灵体的再现
Eisenheim has given us hard proof of the soul's immortality.
能以现代科学唯物论的面貌呈现
A spirit has been reaffirmed in the face of modern scientific materialism.
招魂术召回了人性的新道德良知
The work of spiritualism will arouse humanity to a new moral earnestness.
这是一场革命运动
It is a revolutionary movement
我们能让帝国改制成崇高的共和国
and we will turn the empire into a spiritual republic.
你认为艾森瀚是幕后指使者吗？
Do you think Eisenheim's behind all this?
为何得让一位魔术师来烦我？
Why must I be bothered with a magician?
他不是一般的魔术师，王子殿下
He has proven to be more than a magician, your Highness.
他是个术士、骗子
He is a charlatan. He's a faker.
如果他伪装超能力，就以欺诈关他
If he pretends to have supernatural I powers put him on trial for fraud.
首先我们得证明那是骗局才行
First we have to show it as fraud then do it
查出怎么变的，然后逮他
find out how the trick is done and then arrest him.
这只是很粗糙的示范，探长
This is just a rough demonstration, Inspector.
但你可看出它怎么办到
But you can see how it could work.
是的，我懂了，还不错
Yes, I see. Not bad. Not bad.
我们得从艾森瀚那找位内应
We need a spy in Eisenheim's troop.
那些东方人都不肯说
Those Orientals, yhey won't give us anything.
我试过了
I already tried.
那就想别的办法呀
Then try something else.
发生了什么事
What has happened here?
有个戏院的鬼魂在街道上
One of those ghosts from the theatre, down the street.
哪里？
Where!
就在那，还是个小男孩
Right there, and it's a boy.
真令人作呕
Sick.
那东西在哪？
Where is this thing?
那里
Over there.
你看到了吗？
Did you see it?
就在那里
It was right over there.
你要带他去哪
Where are you taking him?
我要知道怎么做的
I want to know how it's done.
先是柳橙树，现在是这个
First the orange tree, now this.
我得和警方分享我的商业机密码？
Do I have to share all my professional secrets with the police?
这回由不得你，否则我得逮捕你
Well, in this case, yes. Or I'll be forced to arrest you.
什么罪名？
On what charge?
先是欺诈
Mmm, well, we'll start with fraud.
恕我打断，探长
Excuse me, Chief Inspector.
怎么了？
What!
你应该看一下窗外
I think you should look outside the window.
他们是谁？
Who are they?
他们都是为他而来的
They are here for him.
你的信众真死忠
Ah, my goodness, you have a devoted following.
他们在期望什么？
What is it they expect of you?
我不知道，你的密探没告诉你？
I have no idea. What do your spies tell you?
也许是你计划要分裂君主政体？
That you plan to separate? the monarchy perhaps?
为什么？
Why?
因为王子是杀人凶手？
Just because the Crown Prince is a murderer?
他没杀人
He's not a murderer.
凶手已入狱认罪了
We have the real murderer in prison. He pleaded guilty.
你们抓错人了
You've got the wrong man.
你根本就不清楚状况
You don't know that.
但你很清楚
No, but you do.
艾森瀚，你也会进监牢
Herr Eisenheim, you will also go to prison
如果你还是不愿解释你的作为
if you don't explain to me what it is you are doing.
如有群众攻击这里，判刑更重
The sentence will be greater if that mob attacks the building.
哎
Well?
你在做什么？停下来
What are you doing? Stop! Stop!
请你们听我说
Listen to me, please. You must listen to me, please.
谢谢你们前来
Thank you all for coming.
我已经与探长谈过，我认为…
I've been speaking with the Chief Inspector,
有个很大的误会
and I think there's been a serious misunderstanding.
你们该知道…
I want you all to know that everything
在我剧院里出现的是幻象
that you have seen in my theatre is an illusion.
是魔术，那是假的
It's a trick. It's not real.
我无法召回亡魂
I can't bring loved ones back from the grave.
我不能接收另一世界的讯息
I can't receive messages from the other side.
抱歉，我不该让你们误会
I apologize if I've given you any false hope.
我目的只是娱乐
My intention has only been to entertain.
仅此而已
Nothing more.
谢谢你们的支持，回家吧
Now I appreciate your support, but you must go home.
拜托你们，走吧
Please, you must go.
我解释过就不算欺诈，能走了吗？
There, now I've explained it. So it can't be fraud. May I go?
他也唬住你了吗？
Has he tricked you? Is that it?
不，王子殿下
No, your Highness.
那为何让我失望？
Then why are you failing me?
我以为我能信任你
I thought I could trust you.
我以为我登基时可以提拔你
I thought you were a man I could bring with me when I took the throne.
我看错你了吗？
Am I wrong about you?
不，你没错，王子殿下
No. You're not wrong, your Highness, no.
我需要能圆满达成任务之人
I need men who can complete the tasks assigned to them!!
我身边都是笨蛋
Instead I'm surrounded by fools.
最后总要我自己出马
In the end I must do everything myself.
这回也不会有何不同
I can see this case will be no different.
我看起来如何？
How do I look?
很像一般人，王子殿下，非常一般
Ordinary, your Highness, very ordinary.
我想我会乐在其中
I think I'm going to enjoy this.
他们认不出你
They don't recognize you.
好，离远点，我不想和警察站一起
Good. Now keep your distance. I don't want to be seen with a policeman.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是特森女爵吗？
Are you Duchess Von Teschen?
是的
Yes.
你发生什么事？
What's happened to you?
她是被谋杀的，你是被谋杀的吗？
She was murdered. Were you murdered?
谁下的手？他们抓对人了吗？
By who? Did they arrest the right man?
请告诉我们，谁杀了你
Tell us, please. Who murdered you?
某人就在这里
Someone... here.
告诉我们，把他指出来，是王子吗？
Tell us, point him out. Was it the Crown Prince?
他曾杀过一个女人
He's killed a woman before!
王子又不在这
Word? the Crown Prince isn't even here.
王子杀了她！一定有事发生
The Crown Prince killed her! Something must be done!
探长，你确定你抓对人了吗？
Chief Inspector, are you sure you have the right man?
相当确定，让我过一下
Quite sure. Excuse me.
你调查过王子吗？
Did you investigate the Crown Prince?
如果真是他，他该受到正义制裁
He cannot continue if this is true. He must be brought to justice.
不是真的，魔术不能当证据
It's not true, the magic trick is not evidence.
你名字是？
What is your name?
这有什么关系？
I don't see how that matters.
那建议你谨言慎行，先生
I advise you to watch what you say, sir.
那个女演员根本不像苏菲
That actress didn't even look like Sophie.
观众真蠢
But the audience is stupid and he knows it.
他操纵了他们，自己却什么都不说
He manipulates them. He himself said nothing.
女演员也没说什么
His actress said nothing inflammatory.
他让台下观众自行做出指控
He left it to the audience to make their accusations.
那些起哄的人也是他买通的
All taunts paid for by him, of course.
你没记下那些人是谁吧
I don't suppose you made a note of those people?
恐怕今晚人手不够
I'm afraid we didn't have enough men tonight.
下次表演时，我要他们通通就逮
At the next performance I want them all arrested,
艾森瀚与他的同伙
every one of them-Eisenheim and the whole troupe.
我要拿他来杀鸡儆猴
I want to have an example made of him in front of all his followers.
你昨晚真愚蠢，你毁不了他的
That was very foolish last night. You can't destroy him, you know.
你无法扳倒君主政体
You can't bring down the monarchy.
我知道我不行
Oh, I know I can't.
那就别再召唤她，不要挑起问题
Then don't raise her again! Don't provoke those questions.
艾森瀚，我不想抓你
Herr Eisenheim, I don't want to arrest you.
我很愤世嫉俗
I'm a cynical man, God knows.
即使你的表演是真的，我承认
But if your manifestations are somehow real-
你是很特别的人，即使只是戏法
and even I'm willing to admit you're a very special person,
我也得说它令人印象深刻
and if it's a trick then it's equally impressive--
无论如何，你很有天分，别逼我抓你
Either way you have a gift, so don't make me put you in jail.
答应我不会再有下次
Promise me you won't do it again.
我答应你会喜欢接下来的演出
I promise you you'll enjoy this next show.
你到底要什么？
What do you want?
什么都不要
Nothing.
那为何带她回来？
Then why bring her back?
只想与她在一起
Just to be with her.
与她在一起
To be with her.
-都准备好了吗？　　　-是的，长官
-Everything is ready?    -Yes, sir.
我们正在预测他会怎么逃跑
We're trying to assess how he might escape.
他逃不了，每道门窗都要有人看守
He will not escape! I want guards at every door and window!
是的
Sir.
我要为我最近的举止道歉
I want to apologize to you for my behavior of late.
我想补偿你，希望你听听这个提议
But I want to make it up to you if you'll listen to a proposition.
这我不知道
Well, I don't know.
我会让你值回票价的，约瑟
I'll make it worth your while, Josef.
我现在很忙，我可不是…
You know, I'm very busy right now.
闲闲没事做，等着你来
I haven't just been sitting around waiting for you.
不，你当然不是
No, no, of course.
我要你接管我所有的金钱与财物
I want you to assume control of all my finances and my assets.
全部
Everything.
全部？
Everything?
是的，包括这间剧院…
Yes, including this theatre
和今晚的收入
and all the receipts from tonight's performance,
这是我最诚挚的谢意
which I offer with my sincere thanks.
你意下如何？
What do you say?
好吧，我答应
All right, I'll do it.
很好
Good. Good.
你要我介绍你出场吗？
Would you like me to introduce you tonight?
不，今晚就好好欣赏演出吧
No. Tonight just enjoy the show.
探长，我是约瑟费雪，艾森瀚的经理
Excuse me, Chief Inspector, I'm Josef Fischer, Eisenheim's manager.
我记得
Yes, I remember.
发生什么事？怎么都是警察
What's going on? Why all the police?
只是预防措施，费雪先生
Precautions, Herr Fischer, precautions.
你计划逮捕艾森瀚吗？
Are you planning to arrest Eisenheim?
这就取决于他了
That's entirely up to him.
那是特森女爵
It's Duchess Von Teschen.
你为何被谋杀？
Why were you murdered?
我要离开他
I was leaving him.
离开谁？
Leaving who?
王子吗？
The Crown Prince?
当然是王子殿下了
Of course it was the Crown Prince.
这我们可不能忍受
We won't stand for it!
我试着逃跑
I tried to get away.
我死时戴着项链，现在却弄丢了
I was wearing my locket when I died but now it's gone.
不见了
It's lost.
请告诉我们，是谁杀了你？
Tell us, please, who murdered you?
是王子殿下吗？
Was it the Crown Prince?
我们得做些什么？
We must do something!
行动！
Get up!
我代表国王陛下与维也纳市…
In the name of his Imperial Majesty and the city of Vienna,
逮捕爱德华艾维兹…
I hereby arrest Eduard Abramovitz,
魔术师艾森瀚
also known as Eisenheim the Illusionist,
罪名是妨害公共秩序，欺诈…
on charges of disturbing public order, charlatanism,
以及危害国家安全
and threats against the empire!
找到他！
Find him!
他人在哪？
Where is he?
他刚才还在那里
He was right there.
他的戏法怎么变的？    -不是戏法
-How is his trick done?    -No trick.
怎么变的？
How is it done!
我不知道，没人知道
I don't know. Nobody knows.
该死！
Dammit!
我请随从把剑送到警察总署
I had my driver take the sword to police headquarters.
我的手下会检查宝石…
My men will examine it and see
与女爵身上的是否相符
if it matches the gemstone found on Duchess Von Teschen's body.
我想不会错
I have no doubt that it will.
接着我进来，你问我为何迟到
And after that, I came in here and you asked me why I was late.
你偷了皇家的财产
You've stolen Imperial property.
和谋杀相比，简直无足轻重
That seems trivial compared with murder.
就算是真的，也不属于你的管辖
Even if that were true, you have no jurisdiction here.
是的
That's right.
你可以肆无忌惮
You may do as you wish here without consequence.
没人能处罚你，但有一人例外
Nobody can punish you, except one man.
是谁？
Who's that?
国王
The Emperor.
他不会传位给杀人凶手，你杀了人吗？
I don't suppose he'll leave his crown to a murderer, do you?
他不会相信你的
He'll never believe you.
也许
Maybe not.
但我写信给参谋和盘托出
But I wrote a letter to his general staff telling them everything.
包括你意图谋反的计划
Including your plan to overthrow the Emperor.
他们会重视这件事
I know they'll listen to that.
你当不上国王的，我帮不了你
You'll not take the throne, not with my help.
你不想当警察总长？
You no longer want to be Chief of Police?
维也纳市长？
Mayor of Vienna?
也不想封爵或贵族？
You don't want to be a baron, an aristocrat?
恐怕这不是目前的重点
I'm afraid that's out of the question at this point.
你这蠢蛋，他在耍你，在利用你
You fool, he's tricking you. He's manipulating you.
他在表演时曾拿过剑
He had the sword at the command performance.
他大可撬松宝石，用来裁赃
He could have pried the stones loose  then and planted them here.
他策划所有一切    -你喝醉了…
-He's planted everything.    -You were drunk..
一切都是戏法，一切都是假象
It's all a trick. It's an illusion.
假象背后也许就是真相
Perhaps there's truth in this illusion.
你得拍电报给随从，把剑拿回来
You need to wire your driver and have the sword returned.
不然怎样
Or what?
我会杀了你，也许我到头来都会杀你
I'll shoot you. Perhaps I'll shoot you anyway.
那你就杀了一位警探与女爵
And then you'll have killed a police inspector and a Duchess.
或者你该自杀
Or perhaps you'll kill yourself.
你因办事不力…而自我了断
You, uh, committed suicide, distraught at having failed your leader.
我想是参谋部的人
Ah, some officers of the general staff I'd guess.
他们应该已收到我的信
They must've received my letter.
你到底要什么？
What do you want?
我什么都不要
I don't want anything.
很好，你也不配得到
Fine. Fine. You shall have nothing.
各位男士
Gentlemen.
明显地…
The situation is so obvious.
这里全是一群饭桶
Everyone's completely incompetent.
我的父亲治国无方，却没人发现
My father runs the Empire into the ground and no one notices.
没有人有所行动
No one does anything about it.
我想整顿，你们却以背叛回报
I propose to cleanup the mess and you thank me by betraying me.
你们都不重要了，你们会被取代
Well, you're all becoming irrelevant. You'll all be replaced.
这国家将由杂种治理
The country will be run by mongrels.
不同意见在呐喊着，却无人问津
A thousand different voices screaming to be heard and nothing will be done!
无人问津
Nothing!
我已尽力了
I've done everything I can!
太尽力了
Too much! Far too much.
殿下，你在里面吗？开门！
Your Highness, are you in there? Your Highness, open door.
请你开门
Please, open the door.
奉国王之令，我希望你开门
By your father's authority I insist you open the door.
你必须开门！
You must open the door!
你们这些笨蛋
You're all fools...
请开门，殿下
Please, your Highness.
我受不了了，我再也受不了了
And I can't stand it. I won't stand it.
把门撞开！
Break down the door. Break it down!
发生什么事？
What happened?
王子殿下刚才自杀了
The Crown Prince just shot himself.
你是乌尔探长吗？
Are you Chief Inspector Uhl?
我曾经是
I used to be.
你！是谁给你的，是谁？
You! Who gave you this! Who gave you this!
艾森瀚
Herr, Eisenheim!
何时给的？
When!
全部上车！
All aboard!
车票与文件
Tickets and papers.
全部上车！
All aboard!
事情完成之后
When it's done...
你和她先走，我随后会跟上
...you'll travel ahead with her and I shall follow.
她清楚这件事的后果吗？
And she understands everything this entails?
完全清楚
Completely.
你认为艾森瀚是幕后指使者吗？
Do you think Eisenheim's behind all this?
死亡的意义到底为何？
So, what does it mean to die?
你到底要什么？
What do you want?
和她在一起
To be with her.
探长，有件事该让你知道…
Chief Inspector, there's one thing you should know.
您的剑真漂亮，能让我看看吗？
Your sword is very beautiful. Might I see it?
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
You were drunk.
他是术士、骗子
He's a charlatan and he's a faker.
一切都是他策划的
He's plotted everything.
你看到的都是幻象
Everything you have seen is an illusion.
一切都是魔术
It's a trick.